Guide to the Nicholas School of the Environment Reference Collection, 1930-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Nicholas School of the Environment Reference collection 1930-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
1.0 Linear Feet approx. 200 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Nicholas School of the Environment Reference Collection was compiled from various sources by University Archives staff for reference and research.
Historical Note
The Nicholas School celebrates it creation date as 1991, but it represents a coming together of three entities that are almost as old as the university itself. The School of Forestry and Environmental Studies and the Duke University Marine Lab (both formed in 1938) came together in 1991 to become the School of Environment, which was named the Nicholas School in 1995 following a $20 million gift from Peter M. and Ginny Nicholas of Boston.
In 1997, the Department of Geology (formed in 1936) joined the school as the Division of Earth and Ocean Sciences, bringing with it new resources and a new name for the school in December 2000-the Nicholas School of the Environment and Earth Sciences. In December 2003, the Nicholases ended the Campaign for Duke with a $70 million pledge to the university, to help fund the design and construction of Nicholas Hall, the future home of the Nicholas School, as well as the launch of the affiliated Nicholas Institute for Environmental Policy Solutions. In August 2008, the school's name was shortened to the Nicholas School of the Environment, following approval by the Duke University Board of Trustees.
Collection Overview
The collection contains clippings, some administration lists, newsletters, reports, and printed matter for several parts of the Nicholas School of the Environment, including the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, the Dept. of Geology, and the Marine Laboratory. Also included is information on Duke Forest. The collection ranges in date from 1930-ongoing.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. School of the Environment
Nicholas School of the Environment (Duke University) -- History.
Nicholas School of the Environment and Earth Sciences (Duke University) -- History
Duke University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies
Duke University. Dept. of Geology
Duke Forest (Durham, N.C.)
Duke University. Marine Laboratory
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.)
Related Material
Forestry Club Records, 1962-1976
University Archives, Duke University.
Marine Laboratory Records, 1945 - 1990.
University Archives, Duke University.
Nicholas School of the Environment, Center for Continuing Education records, 1992-1999.
University Archives, Duke University.
Nicholas School Master's Projects, 1988-2005
University Archives, Duke University.
School of Forestry and Environmental Studies Subject Collection, circa 1960-1979
University Archives, Duke University.
Departments and Academic Divisions Reference Collection
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Forestry and Environmental Studies, School of - Administration, 1930-ongoing (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association, SFES, 1985
  - Alumni Newsletter, 1959, 1994
  - Annual Report, 1977-1978
  - Progress Report, 1991/92, 1992/93
  - Annual Report, 1999
  - Proceedings, 50th Anniversary Symposium, 1988 Oct.
  - 50th Anniversary Promotional Packets, 1988
  - Doris Duke Conservation Fellows, 2001
  - Intensive Course Program/Continuing Education, 1980s-1990s
  - Miscellaneous Printed Matter
  - Clippings, 1980s-ongoing
  - Duke Forest - Clippings, 1990s-ongoing
  - Duke Forest - Land Acquisition (Box 2)
  - Duke Forest - Reports
  - Duke Forest - Miscellaneous Printed Matter
  - Geology - Printed Matter
  - Geology - Clippings, 1970s-ongoing
  - Marine Laboratory - Administration, 1971-1978
  - Marine Laboratory - Printed Matter and Clippings